July 30th, Stellar Year 2149
Giad Federacy Forward Operating Base FOB13
Last one.
Did you actually read those?
It's rare for you to end up
at the same base as me.
Supposedly we'll all be together tomorrow.
I don't really care.
But do you think they could
treat us a little different?
These things are prototypes, after all.
We took some heavy hits yesterday.
Are you thinking it's about time
for them to come?
No. I guess you could say
they could come at any time.
Our analysis of the increase
in comms traffic, as well as the reports
from our autonomous scouts,
shows a high probability
of a large-scale Legion attack
in the coming days.
That's the Joint Analysis Team's conclusion.
So it's finally coming...
What is it, Colonel Wenzel?
I assume we'll be reorganizing our units
to prepare for the attack.
I'd like my men back.
The Reginleifs are still
in the prototype stage.
With no idea whether they're capable
of operating effectively on their own,
it's safest to keep them grouped
with Vánagandrs, as we've been doing.
Sir, I understand your position,
but Nordlicht squadron's total kill count
is among the best in the 8th Corps.
As are their losses.
Consider it a filtering process.
All you're doing is taking advantage
of the Eighty-Six's experience!
Sending those poor kids
right back into the war...
You're a merchant of death,
desperate to get back your lost position!
My new Feldreß, the MX2 Reginleif,
has even greater mobility than the Legion.
If we're going to prepare
for this large-scale offensive,
do we not need to break
with traditional tactical doctrine
and have a small elite unit capable
of battling a much larger force?
To protect the Federacy, and its people...
I hope you'll consider
allowing my Reginleifs,
as well as Nordlicht squadron,
to be put to their proper use, General.
July 31st, Stellar Year 2149
Reporting, Squadron Commander.
There were two casualties in the battle yesterday,
putting us under twenty men.
We're just out here on loan from the labs,
and a group of foreigners, too.
And our commander is the famous spider-woman,
the weirdest girl even among
the lab weirdos or the brass.
We're asking for more men,
but they won't send anyone.
I'm used to not having additional men.
Your life would've been easier
if you'd joined one of the regular units.
I feel more at home here.
As long as you don't get us killed
with idiotic orders,
even if you're a bratty little kid
who never smiles,
or who puts himself
at the head of every charge,
or a Reaper who'll drive you crazy
if you try to sympathize with us,
it doesn't matter to me.
Lieutenant? Lieutenant?
Change before your leave your room.
Kiri, I was combing my hair.
Frederica!
Shinei. Sorry, I got it wrong.
Yesterday was rough.
Anju, sorry.
Frederica?
Theo, go get a uniform!
Huh?
Um...
I just got here!
Oh, you got another present.
The idea of Eighty-Six as poor, helpless children
is really getting out of control.
Get rid of them all.
Don't even tell me about them.
I'd love to,
but I need to follow the rules.
Militaries are organizations
filled with inefficient, illogical humans.
So, this concludes your report,
squadron commander.
Per the rules, please sign here!
Eat, Frederica.
No true lady should let herself
be seen like that!
Who's a "lady"?
The biggest problem was that
you were half-asleep
and half-naked,
wandering around the base.
Who told you, Raiden?
Hey, guys!
You can be mean.
All I said was that if you can't even manage
to dress yourself out here,
you'd be better off at the base.
Mascots aren't asked
to follow military orders.
We'd feel better
if you were at the rear.
I can't do that.
I'm here to see this to the end.
Make sure you don't wander around the base
half-asleep and half-naked anymore, then.
Half-naked?!
Get this—
Don't tell her!
Half-naked?
Stop talking about that!
It's been a long time since
all of you have been together, right?
That's right!
Kurena, calm down.
We won't be together long, though.
We'll be starting clean-up, I guess.
Repairing damaged defenses,
recovering the remains
of allied and enemy weapons...
Bodies, too.
The mechanized units got hit hard.
We might get sent on a patrol.
Even though we know there's no point...
We can't explain that, though.
Yeah...
Jeez...
You've become used to being lackeys
for the whole army.
Today, we're heading back to our base!
Giad Federacy 177th Division Command Post
Welcome back!
First, thank you for all the rescue
and support missions you've been doing.
It looks like the Reginleifs work better
with you and the Foreign units.
What do you think, Lieutenant?
Do you like them?
I've submitted my evaluation
alongside that of the Para-RAID.
Yup. So now I want to hear
how you feel about them.
You used Feldreßes of similar types
back in the Republic, right?
If you're asking about the
Juggernauts you made...
Reginleifs.
Juggernauts.
Reginleifs!
Fine.
And?
They're aluminum coffins, slightly better
than the ones the Republic had.
Really?
Did she not know?
Those things were only designed
for mobility, not safety.
They're responsible for the deaths
of several Processors.
We only barely manage to use them
because we're experienced.
They're "slightly better"
than the ones that made me
doubt the sanity
of the idiot who made them?
The guys who piloted them were crazy, too!
It was all we were given.
I see.
They're not bad. I don't think.
Though they do require a
certain sort of Processor.
I appreciate their speed,
and they're fast, but also very precise.
They're highly maneuverable.
I see.
For some reason I don't think
I'm being complimented.
He's not complimenting her, is he?
So why'd you agreed to be an operator?
I'm told it was you
who recommended us.
As test pilots.
I'm actually opposed to child soldiers
like you being sent to the front lines.
Especially Eighty-Six like you.
I was a Vánagandr pilot.
When the war with the Legion
started ten years ago,
I was your age.
A lot of my friends died
because of those slow-ass Vánagandr.
I told myself so many times
that a faster Feldreß could've saved their lives.
That's why I made the Reginleifs.
Thank you for your honest opinion, Lieutenant.
I'll make you give me a better one
with the next round of upgrades.
Look forward to it.
Now, I've got good news
before I give you the message.
The other day we were finally able
to confirm the survival
of the United Kingdom of Roa Gracia
and the Alliance of Wald.
According to the wireless transmissions
we received,
What countries are those?
they've managed to build defensive lines
and maintain an area they could survive in.
They're to the north and south.
We learned that in officer's school!
Did we?
However, the other surrounding nations,
as well as the
Republic of San Magnolia to the west,
are still not answering our radio messages.
So is the message a bad one, ma'am?
It is, unfortunately.
We're predicting a
large-scale Legion attack soon.
The Western Theater Army
will be strengthening its forces
and reorganizing its chain of command.
The 1028th Test Unit will be placed
under the 177th Mechanized,
and I will be taking command.
It's time for the Nordlicht squadron,
and my Reginleifs, to shine!
Any questions?
What is the size of the offensive?
We expect to be able to beat it back
easily with our current forces.
You'd sent me a message
about something similar, right?
I read it with great interest,
but the number of enemies
you said were coming is just impossible.
It goes far beyond
what our analysts are saying.
You don't need to be that worried.
The Federacy isn't like the Republic.
We take recon and analysis seriously.
And we prepare properly.
And more than anything, the Federacy will never
abandon those who fight alongside it.
What is it?
Would you quit your hobby
of walking in complete silence?
It's so dreary in here.
You should put up a painting
or a photo or something.
It's so desolate.
All I do here is sleep.
If I have more things,
it makes it harder to clean.
It's not just a place to sleep.
It's a place to live.
A place to call home.
It's not good to leave it empty.
Maybe that was okay
in the Republic, but...
Eugene's room was filled with photos.
You were the one who cleaned it?
There aren't enough hands
to do all the work that needs doing.
I helped go through his things.
It was all photos of his sister.
You shouldn't have talked to him.
Then you wouldn't have had
to see him die.
I don't think so.
Even if death
will eventually tear you apart,
it's better to meet someone
than not meet them.
You can remember that.
If there's no need, you shouldn't get involved
in someone else's death.
You're one to talk.
Mr. Kind and Gentle Reaper.
Why did you come here?
Um, well...
I'm sorry about this morning,
when I said "Kiri"...
Are we that similar?
Yeah.
Not like twins, but very similar!
My knight, Kiriya Nouzen, was a member
of the Nouzen clan like you.
He wasn't a direct descendant of the clan,
so he wasn't really related to you.
But he was four years
older than you...
So when I saw him last,
he looked how you do now.
In a fortress filled with adults,
he was the only one I could play with.
He would comb my hair,
get me flowers from the garden...
No matter what selfish things I asked for,
he would never get upset.
He was really serious about everything.
And stubborn, too.
I'm sure if he met you,
you wouldn't get along at all.
Here.
Which?
This one!
"When you talk to someone, close your book!"
"Follow the rules and regulations!"
He was all about that stuff.
I'm sure you'd ignore all that,
which would just make him madder.
I can almost see it.
Why did he become a Legion?
It's my fault.
The Giad Empire used the Legion
to attack our neighbors.
But after that, the people rebelled,
and the Imperial family was chased
to a border fortress.
The Legion were supposed to protect us
in our soldiers' stead,
but ironically...
Well, I don't know what happened exactly.
But the Legion weren't built
to fight alongside humans.
So we had to use human defenders
at the fortress.
And Kiriya had to fight to protect me
against the rebelling people.
You mean the current Federacy Army.
Yes.
He killed many of them.
And eventually, he went insane.
He lost his family, everyone he knew...
The home he grew up in
was enemy territory.
And the other members
of the royal guard alongside him
fell one after another,
like tines falling from a comb.
I think he lost too much.
Eventually fighting for my sake
became all he had.
I would often see him smiling at me,
crushing a Federacy soldier
beneath his boot,
a bloodstained Feldreß at his side...
With a calm, bright look on his face...
And I was so scared.
Eventually, the fortress fell,
and the Federacy caught us.
I was lucky that Ernst was there
to inspire his men.
Thanks to him, the only thing
that was shown to the crowd
as proof of my death
was the Imperial mantle I wore.
But Kiriya saw it...
And at that moment,
the Legion were wandering the battlefield
and looking for things they could recycle.
Kiriya stood there, not moving,
and he did not run.
I turned him into that monster.
And in the end...
the Empire fell, and many died.
And only the Legion were left.
You said they're coming, right?
Kiri will be there, too.
When that happens...
I understand.
You don't.
If it gets dangerous, run.
Don't fight.
I'd forgotten how easily people die.
No matter how you want them
to have a future...
You were right a moment ago.
I don't want the people I've met to die.
Saving Kiriya isn't worth
your or the others' deaths.
You all have a future,
and that cannot be taken from you.
A future?
I knew it.
You've never even thought about it.
Jeez...
It's not a good example,
but you should take a lesson from Eugene.
Your next leave.
Where you want to go.
What you want to do someday.
Anything like that will do.
What's so funny?
No, someone once said
the same thing to me.
And what did you say?
That I'd never thought about it.
How boring.
Even your heart is dreary.
That person must've been disappointed.
Maybe so.
What are you doing?
She likes you, big brother.
I just remind her of someone.
That knight?
But isn't it the same for you?
You seem to have taken
a real liking to her.
Maybe.
She's the same as the old me.
I don't know about that.
Kurena, come pick up the princess.
Hey, wait.
You gave them a warning, huh?
I figured I may as well try.
I told you when we came here
to keep that power of yours a secret.
You haven't forgotten
what they called you
when they found out
you could hear those voices, Reaper.
The Federacy aren't the saints
they think they are.
And even here,
we're not treated as their equals.
It isn't just the Legion that likes
to take out people's brains.
If you want to be a guinea pig,
that's up to you,
but I don't want to end up
a hostage to encourage you.
Don't do anything stupid.
Sorry.
The warning you gave them
is enough on its own.
It's up to them if they want to believe.
But... are you okay?
What do you mean?
You're not thinking of anything
you don't need to be, are you?
Is what Ernst said bothering you?
The future?
Yeah.
Frederica told me to think about it.
But I never have.
I've never needed to.
You?
I think it'll all work out.
It can't be harder
than fighting the Legion.
It was always about this time of day,
wasn't it?
You think the Major's doing okay?
"Even so."